Guide to the Richard Erdoes Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- 2010 Addition, 1920-2008; 49.08; (121 boxes) + 1 broadside
  - Audiovisual Materials, 1968-1998; Series III; 6.26; (15 boxes)
    - Crow Dog Dup #2, undated; WAMSSS2609_0007; 1; 00:58:56 (Box 311, Item barcode 39002102370120)
    - Ken Burns presents The West, a film by Stephen Ives, 1996; 9; 9 VHS videocassettes (Box 312)
      This set of audiocassettes is commericial. They have not been digitized.
    - Wounded Knee - Mary Crow Dog - Reports Rapid City - KPFK Folio for the Blind, 1974 May; 1 (Box 313, Item barcode 39002104612404)
    - Mary Crow Dog, undated; 1 (Box 313, Item barcode 39002104612412)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 313, Item barcode 39002104612420)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 313, Item barcode 39002104612438)
    - Peyote, undated; 1 (Box 313, Item barcode 39002104612446)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 313, Item barcode 39002104612453)
    - Garland of Roses, etc., 1969 August 29; 1 (Box 313, Item barcode 39002104612461)
      The audiotape reel reads: "Little Havens for My Darlings, Beauty of My Mother's Prayer, As We Grow Older, Will Leave a Memory.", 1st and 2nd tune recorded, Rising Wind.
  - Slides, 1972-1997; Series IV; 0.75; (3 boxes)
    - "New Mexico and Indian Art, modern", 1975-1984; 27 slides (Box 314)
    - "Death cart", 1984-1997; 11 slides (Box 314)
    - "Denver Art Museum", undated; 5 slides (Box 314)
    - "Carson House", 1984; 1 slide (Box 314)
    - "Indian Vendors", 1975 September; 21 slides (Box 314)
    - "Pet Parade", 1986 September; 52 slides (Box 314)
    - "Altars", 1984, undated; 50 slides (Box 314)
    - "Santos", 1981 July; 5 slides (Box 314)
    - "Church of Las Trampas, Taos, New Mexico", 1982-1988; 32 slides (Box 314)
    - "Chimayo", 1972-1984; 105 slides (Box 314)
    - "Madrid, New Mexico", 1975-1982; 14 slides (Box 314)
    - "Zozobra", 1975 September; 17 slides (Box 314)
    - "Southern Highland University, New Mexico", 1997 June; 13 slides (Box 314)
    - "Mountain Air, New Mexico", 1998; 35 slides (Box 314)
    - "Las Vegas, New Mexico", 1988, 1997; 30 slides (Box 314)
    - "Ranchos de Taos", 1981-1989; 28 slides (Box 314)
    - "Los Lucernos, New Mexico", 1998 June; 11 slides (Box 314)
    - "Mountain cross on Taos highway", 1977, 1989; 7 slides (Box 314)
    - "Fancy cement wall, Mountain Air, New Mexico", 1978; 8 slides (Box 314)
    - "Tierra Amarilla and Brazos cliffs, New Mexico", 1981 July; 2 slides (Box 314)
    - Unidentified, 1987-1998; 56 slides (Box 314)
    - "Lakota Woman, Siege at Wounded Knee", 1993; 210 slides (Box 315)
    - "Anasazi", 1999; 24 slides (Box 315)
    - "My Anasazi illustrations", 1981; 28 slides (Box 315)
    - "El Paso", 1980-1994; 34 slides (Box 315)
    - "Albuquerque, New Mexico", 1975-1984; 23 slides (Box 315)
    - "Old New York City", 1996-1991; 17 slides (Box 315)
    - "Puerto Rico in New York City", 1984; 59 slides (Box 315)
    - "Las Golondrinas Festival, Pecos, New Mexico", 1978-1979, undated; 85 slides (Box 315)
    - "Procession and mass, Las Golondrinas, Santa Fe, New Mexico", 1979-1981, undated; 29 slides (Box 315)
    - "Las Golondrinas Mattachine dancers, New Mexico", 1979-1990; 73 slides (Box 315)
    - "Processional and mass, Pecos, New Mexico", 1985-1988, undated; 39 slides (Box 315)
    - "Pecos, New Mexico", 1985-1988, undated; 20 slides (Box 315)
    - "Las Golondrinas, New Mexico", 1978-1994, undated; 79 slides (Box 315)
    - "Veggie vendor and crosses, Las Golondrinas", 1978-1987, uncated; 18 slides (Box 315)
    - "Breadmaking, Las Golondrinas", 1979-1989, undated; 21 slides (Box 315)
    - Unidentified, 1990-1998, undated; 12 slides (Box 315)
    - "Rodeo Galisteo", 1989; 34 slides (Box 316)
    - "Winter", 1977-1988; 9 slides (Box 316)
    - "Fall", 1987-1990; 106 slides (Box 316)
    - "Erich, Rick Ulli, Thomas, Pa and Ma", 1988-1997, undated; 18 slides (Box 316)
    - "Erich Ulli wedding", 1996; 78 slides (Box 316)
    - "Kite F[east?]", 1992; 11 slides (Box 316)
    - "Rafting", 1989, undated; 8 slides (Box 316)
    - "Terry Haas, Margie", 1991-1996; 25 slides (Box 316)
    - "Friends", 1989-1990; 19 slides (Box 316)
    - "Seattle", 1991; 82 slides (Box 316)
    - "Winter", 1989-1991; 19 slides (Box 316)
    - L. A. march, Pasadena", 1990; 42 slides (Box 316)
    - "Eddie Daniels", 1989-1990; 58 slides (Box 316)
    - "Cemetery, Galisteo", 1990-1992; 27 slides (Box 316)
    - "Bikers meet, Sturgis, South Dakota", 1991; 29 slides (Box 316)
    - "Bikers", 1992, undated; 10 slides (Box 316)
    - Motorcycle race, Zandvoort, Holland, undated; 1 slide (Box 316)
    - "Jackie and family", 1972, 1992-1996; 74 slides (Box 316)
    - "Mosque Abiquiu, New Mexico", 1993 October; 27 slides (Box 316)
    - "Masse sculptura", 1994; 20 slides (Box 316)
    - Artwork, 1993; 7 slides (Box 316)
    - "New Mexico scenes", 1975-1993, undated; 56 slides (Box 316)
    - "Colorado", 1991; 20 slides (Box 316)
  - Electronic Files, undated; Series V; 0.21; (1 box)
    Box 317 (electronic disk): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - A Good Day to Fight: the Autobiography of Dennis Banks Dennis Banks with Richard Erdoes, MS Word, undated; 1 zip disk (Box 317)
      2011.wa.2609-0001
  - Posters and Artwork, 1970-1995; Series VI; 0.58; (3 boxes) + 1 broadside
    - "The Journey," Marv Swallow, Rosebud Sioux, color pencil art, undated (Box 318 (Oversize))
    - Artwork, 1979-1990, undated; 2 (Box 318 (Oversize))
    - Dennis Banks poster and unidentified portrait, undated (Box 318 (Oversize))
    - Crow Dog posters, 1975 (Box 318 (Oversize))
    - Wounded Knee, South Dakota Quadrangle, USGS map, 1967 (Box 318 (Oversize))
    - Wounded Knee posters and ephemera, circa 1973; 2 (Box 318 (Oversize))
    - Oversize photograph - "Camilla Smith" inscribed on reverse, undated (Box 318 (Oversize))
    - Photograph of 3 people, undated (Box 318 (Oversize))
    - "Coal Black Death - Lame Deer Montana," artwork and poster, undated (Box 318 (Oversize))
    - Pencil and pen drawings accompanied by writings and correspondence, undated (Box 318 (Oversize))
    - Free Crowdog! 4 posters, undated (Box 318 (Oversize))
    - Miscellaneous posters, ephemera, undated (Box 318 (Oversize))
    - Shipping labels: posters, 1969 and 2010, 2010, undated (Box 318 (Oversize))
    - "Ghost Dance of the Red Nations," poster, 1975 December 3 (Box 319 (Oversize))
    - "Big Mountain Independent Diné Nation, 10 Years of Resistance - Sundance Memorial, August 23-26, 1984," poster (Box 319 (Oversize))
    - "The North American Indian calendar," Edward S. Curtis, 1981 (Box 319 (Oversize))
    - "Support the Longest Walk," poster, 1978 (Box 319 (Oversize))
    - "I Want You for the U.S. Cavalry," poster of General Custer, 1974 (Box 319 (Oversize))
    - Native American Calendar, partial, 1974 (Box 319 (Oversize))
    - Native American Calendar - "We Are the Land's People", 1975 (Box 319 (Oversize))
    - "Educational posters about history of white-Native American relations", undated; 2 (Box 319 (Oversize))
    - "The Hole: Minnesota State Prison at Stillwater," 2 posters, "Liberty Bull: It's not what it's cracked up to be!," 2 posters with note from Chris Spotted Eagle, 1976, 1981 (Box 319 (Oversize))
    - "Sundance at Crow Dog's Paradise," 10 posters, 1977 (Box 319 (Oversize))
    - "To Mr., Mrs. Erdose-n-family [sic], from: Wicahpi Wahcala Tiwahe," painting on plywood, undated (Box 320 (Oversize))
    - Three contemporary Native American art prints by Dan V. Lomahaftewa, signed, 1993, undated (Box 321 (Broadside))
    - Calendar of Events, Eight Northern Indian Pueblos Council, 1977 (Box 321 (Broadside))
    - "First Annual Red Nation Celebration, Saturday, August 19, 1995," poster, 1995 August 9 (Box 321 (Broadside))
    - "Oglala Lakota College 84/85," poster, 1984-1985 (Box 321 (Broadside))
    - "Grand Opening: Indian Pueblo Cultural Center, Inc., August 28, 1976," poster (Box 321 (Broadside))
    - "The Eagle Speaks - Vision Quest Series," print, [1977] (Box 321 (Broadside))